[
   {
     "question": "Botulinum toxin blocks the release of acetylcholine from cholinergic nerve terminals. Which of the following is a possible effect of botulinum toxin?",
     "answer": "Skeletal muscle paralysis"
   },
   {
     "question": "A dentist would like to reduce salivation in a patient in preparation for an oral surgical procedure. Which of the following strategies will be useful in reducing salivation?",
     "answer": "Block muscarinic receptors in the salivary glands"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is a systemic effect of a muscarinic agonist?",
     "answer": "Reduced heart rate (bradycardia)"
   },
   {
     "question": "An elderly female who lives in a farm house was brought to the emergency room in serious condition after ingesting a liquid from an unlabeled bottle found near her bed, apparently in a suicide attempt. She presented with diarrhea, frequent urination, convulsions, breathing difficulties, constricted pupils (miosis), and excessive salivation. Which of the following is correct regarding this patient?",
     "answer": "She most likely consumed an organophosphate pesticide."
   },
   {
     "question": "Sarin is a volatile nerve agent that inhibits cholinesterase enzymes. Which of the following symptoms would you expect to see in a patient exposed to sarin?",
     "answer": "Constriction of pupils (miosis)"
   },
   {
     "question": "Head and neck irradiation in cancer patients can decrease salivary secretion and cause dry mouth. All of the following drugs or classes of drugs are theoretically useful in improving secretion of saliva in these patients except:",
     "answer": "Muscarinic antagonists"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following drugs or classes of drugs will be useful in treating the symptoms of myasthenia gravis?",
     "answer": "Anticholinesterase agents"
   },
   {
     "question": "Atropa belladonna is a plant that contains atropine (a muscarinic antagonist). Which of the following drugs or classes of drugs will be useful in treating poisoning with belladonna?",
     "answer": "Physostigmine"
   },
   {
     "question": "During an ophthalmic surgical procedure, the surgeon wanted to constrict the pupil of the patient using a miotic drug. However, he accidentally used another drug that caused dilation of the pupil (mydriasis) instead. Most likely, which of the following drugs did he use?",
     "answer": "Tropicamide"
   },
   {
     "question": "Sarin is a nerve gas that is an organophosphate cholinesterase inhibitor. Which of the following could be used as an antidote to sarin poisoning?",
     "answer": "Atropine"
   },
   {
     "question": "Atropine is one of the ingredients in the antidiarrheal combination diphenoxylate/atropine available in the United States. Which of the following effects is produced by atropine that contributes to its antidiarrheal effect?",
     "answer": "Reduction in gastrointestinal motility"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding ganglion blocking drugs?",
     "answer": "Blockade of sympathetic ganglia could result in reduced blood pressure"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding the neuromuscular blockers (NMBs)?",
     "answer": "Cholinesterase inhibitors reduce the effects of nondepolarizing NMBs"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding drug interactions with nondepolarizing neuromuscular blockers (NMBs)?",
     "answer": "Aminoglycosides increase the effects of nondepolarizing NMBs"
   },
   {
     "question": "A patient was administered a neuromuscular blocker (NMB) prior to a surgical procedure to produce skeletal muscle paralysis. This NMB drug affected small, rapidly contracting muscles of the face and eyes first and diaphragm muscles last. The effect of this drug was easily reversed with neostigmine. Which of the following neuromuscular blockers was most likely administered to this patient?",
     "answer": "Rocuronium"
   },
   {
     "question": "A patient was administered a neuromuscular blocker (NMB) prior to a surgical procedure to produce skeletal muscle paralysis. This NMB drug caused initial skeletal muscle fasciculations before the onset of paralysis. The effect of this drug could not be reversed with neostigmine. Which of the following neuromuscular blockers was most likely administered to this patient?",
     "answer": "Succinylcholine"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding adrenergic neurotransmission?",
     "answer": "Tricyclic antidepressants and cocaine prevent reuptake of norepinephrine into the nerve terminals."
   },
   {
     "question": "All of the following are correct regarding adrenergic receptors, except:",
     "answer": "beta2 receptors are found mainly in adipose tissue"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding responses mediated by adrenergic receptors?",
     "answer": "Stimulation of alpha 1 receptors increases blood pressure"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following adrenergic agonists is most likely to cause CNS side effects when administered systemically?",
     "answer": "Ephedrine."
   },
   {
     "question": "A new antihypertensive drug was tested in an animal model of hypertension. The drug when given alone reduces blood pressure in the animal. Norepinephrine when given in the presence of this drug did not cause any significant change in blood pressure or heart rate in the animal. The new drug is similar to which of the following drugs in terms of its pharmacological mechanism of action?",
     "answer": "Carvedilol."
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following drugs is commonly used topically in the treatment of glaucoma?",
     "answer": "Timolol"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding carvedilol?",
     "answer": "Carvedilol has an alpha 1 blocking activity"
   },
   {
     "question": "If an ophthalmologist wants to dilate the pupils for an eye examination, which of the following drugs/classes of drugs could be theoretically useful?",
     "answer": "Muscarinic receptor inhibitor (antagonist)."
   },
   {
     "question": "In Alzheimer's disease, there is a deficiency of cholinergic neuronal function in the brain. Theoretically, which of the following strategies will be useful in treating the symptoms of Alzheimer's disease?",
     "answer": "Inhibiting the acetylcholinesterase enzyme in the brain"
   },
   {
     "question": "A patient with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) was prescribed a beta 2 agonist for the relief of bronchospasm. However, the patient did not respond to this treatment. Which of the following drugs or classes of drugs would you suggest for this patient as the next option?",
     "answer": "Ipratropium"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding alpha-adrenergic blockers?",
     "answer": "alpha -adregenic blockers are used in the treatment of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH)"
   },
   {
     "question": "A beta-blocker was prescribed for hypertension in a female asthma patient. After about a week of treatment, the asthma attacks got worse, and the patient was asked to stop taking the beta-blocker. Which of the following beta-blockers would you suggest as an alternative in this patient that is less likely to worsen her asthma?",
     "answer": "metoprolol"
   },
   {
     "question": "A hypertensive patient was accidentally given an alpha 2 agonist instead of an alpha blocker. Which of the following is correct in this situation?",
     "answer": "alpha 2 agonists can reduce blood pressure in this patient"
   },
   {
     "question": "An asthma patient was given a nonselective beta agonist to relieve bronchoconstriction. Which of the following adverse effects would you expect to see in this patient?",
     "answer": "Tachycardia"
   },
   {
     "question": "One of your patients who is hypertensive and gets mild asthma attacks occasionally bought an herbal remedy online to help with his asthma. He is not on any asthma medications currently but is receiving a beta 1-selective blocker for his hypertension. The herbal remedy seems to relieve his asthma attacks, but his blood pressure seems to increase despite the beta-blocker therapy. Which of the following drugs is most likely present in the herbal remedy he is taking?",
     "answer": "epihedrine"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following drugs would be the most effective anti-motion sickness drug for a person planning to go on a cruise?",
     "answer": "Scopolamine"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 12-year-old boy who is allergic to peanuts was brought to the emergency room after accidentally consuming peanuts contained in fast food. He is in anaphylactic shock. Which of the following drugs would be most appropriate to treat this patient?",
     "answer": "Epinephrine"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 70-year-old patient was brought to the emergency room with a blood pressure of 76/60 mm Hg, tachycardia, and low cardiac output. He was diagnosed with acute heart failure. Which of the following drugs would be the most appropriate to improve his cardiac function?",
     "answer": "Dobutamine"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 60-year-old female patient started on a new antihypertensive medication recently. Her blood pressure seems to be under control, but she complains of fatigue, drowsiness, and fainting when she gets up from the bed (orthostatic hypotension). Which of the following drugs is she most likely taking?",
     "answer": "Prazosin"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 30-year-old male patient was brought to the ER with amphetamine overdose. He presented with high blood pressure and arrhythmia. Which of the following is correct regarding this patient?",
     "answer": "amphetamine can active all types of adregenic receptors"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 70-year-old male needs to be treated with an alpha blocker for overflow incontinence due to his enlarged prostate. Which of the following drugs would you suggest in this patent that will not affect his blood pressure significantly?",
     "answer": "Tamsulosin"
   },
   {
     "question": "A 50-year-old male was brought to the emergency room after being stung by a hornet. The patient was found to be in anaphylactic shock, and the medical team tried to reverse the bronchoconstriction and hypotension using epinephrine. However, the patient did not fully respond to the epinephrine treatment. The patient's wife mentioned that he is taking a prescription medication for his blood pressure, the name of which she does not remember. Which of the following medications is he most likely taking that could have prevented the effects of epinephrine?",
     "answer": "Propranolol"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following is correct regarding beta blockers?",
     "answer": "treatment with beta blockers should not be stopped abruptly"
   },
   {
     "question": "Which of the following adrenergic agonists is commonly present in nasal sprays available over the counter (OTC) to treat nasal congestion?",
     "answer": "Oxymetazoline"
   }
 ]
 